

Paul Fisher

PhD Researcher

I am a researcher in Cognitive Neuroscience, primarily working with eye-tracking behavioural experiments. I have over 4 years of experience with data-analysis (Python, R), project management, and experimental design (MATLAB). My foremost expertise concerns data-science in the topics of temporal perception and visual attention. I have a history with EEG, MRI, and other brain imaging experimental research tools. I also teach neuro-anatomy and neuropsychological testing at the LMU. I have a further interest in C++ and other languages such as SQL. I am familiar with libraries/packages in Python such as: Pandas, Matplotlib, NumPy, bokeh, and in R: dplyr, multicomp, ggplot2, tidyverse, and many more.



p.fisher@psy.lmu.de



+4917624698714



Munich

WORK EXPERIENCE

Ph.D in Visual Attention and Perception LMU, Munich

06/2019 - Present

- Experience with Python, R, and MATLAB to perform data analysis tasks and semiautomation of data pipelines. (Capturing, cleaning, transforming, visualising).
- Published statistical analysis in high impact scientific journals using R packages including: nlme, sjstats, Rmisc, dplyr, ggplot2, rstatix. Including hypothesis testing, mixed effects models, general linear models, and psychometric functions.
- Skills with presenting to large groups e.g. Presentation of data at international scientific conferences.
- Teaching Bachelor students Neuro-Anatomy (Lectures) and Neuropsychological Testing (Seminars).
- Designing and managing projects from theory to published research.
- Running and maintaining testing laboratory (Eye-trackers valued at 9,000€).

Research Assistant in EEG and Data Analysis LMU. Munich

01/2018 - 12/2018

- Semi-automated data pipeline involving data collection, preprocessing, and data transformation using EEGlab and R.
- Project management including recruitment of EEG participants, experiment design (Python), and testing.
- Mentoring Bachelor students.

Data Processing Research Assistant with Clinical Team PRONIA team, Munich

11/2017 - 10/2018

- Data wrangling of large Neuropsychological patient screenings (MATLAB).
- Data digitalisation of patient tests and procedures.
- File management of confidential data.

Clinical Research Assistant

German Center for Vertigo and Balance Disorders

01/2017 - 12/2017

- Prototyping point-of-care application for bedside testing of spatial orientation and memory (Published).
- End user for UAT research, data collection and analysis (SPSS and EXCEL).

EDUCATION

Master of Science - Neuro-Cognitive Psychology LMU, Munich - First Class Honours

10/2016 - 06/2018

Bachelor of Science - Psychology Canterbury Christ Church University - First Class Honours

SKILLS



PUBLICATIONS

Temporal Order Judgements and Presaccadic Shifts of Attention: What can Prior Entry teach us about the Premotor Theory? (Accepted)

- P. Fisher & T. Schenk
- Journal of Vision

A machine learning investigation of volumetric and functional MRI abnormalities in adults born preterm. (2019)

- J Shang, P Fisher, JG Bäuml, M Daamen, N Baumann,...
- Human brain mapping 40 (14), 4239-4252

A bedside application-based assessment of spatial orientation and memory: approaches and lessons learned (2019)

- VL Flanagin, P Fisher, B Olcay, S Kohlbecher, T Brandt
- Journal of neurology 266 (1), 126-138

Evaluation of two observational methods to assess the numbers of nesting puffins (Fratercula arctica) (2017)

- PH B Osthaus, A Farrell, P Fisher
- International Conference in Protecting Biodiversity

LANGUAGES

Enalish

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

German

Elementary Proficiency

INTERESTS

Chess Cooking Reading Fitness Codina Swimming Music